字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
-Are we out of booze? -That's how I dull the pain!
嘿！没酒了吗？
Damn.
该死的
When will we get there? Wherever we're picking up our gold.
我们还没到吗？
Be patient. We're almost there.
耐心点 我们就快到了
EPISODE 5: THE TROLL'S CHILD
第五集：巨怪的孩子
Damn it.
该死的…
ENGLAND, NEAR THE RIVER HUMBER
（英格兰 靠近汉波湖）
Who will watch the ship?
谁来守着船呢？
We're only making a short stop. We won't stay long.
我们只是短暂停一下
Get up!
起来！
Don't run. If you move, I'll hurt you.
嘿 别跑 你敢动我就打你
Let no one escape. It'll be a problem if someone rats us out.
别让任何人跑掉 如果有人把我们说出去 那就麻烦了
Two on the right.
右边有两个
That bastard ate it glady without knowing what it was.
那个家伙真的全吃掉了 根本不知道是什么 就吃得津津有味
My head is pounding.
我的头好疼
You drank too much.
你喝多了
What's wrong? You couldn't sleep?
怎么了？没睡着？
Yeah. There was a gnat buzzing around me last night.
对
A gnat?
蚊子？
What's this? A survivor?
这是什么？漏了没杀掉的？
No, it's him. He's the Troll of Jom's son.
不 是他 约姆的巨怪的儿子
Oh, was he left alive?
哦 他居然还活着
He's working hard so early in the morning.
这么一大早就在努力工作了
I will avenge my father!
我要为我父亲报仇！
I challenge you to a duel!
我要求决斗
Looking good, lad.
小子 真勇敢啊
Oh, my! I'm so scared!
天哪！我好害怕！
What will you do, Askeladd?
阿谢拉特 你打算怎么做？
What a pain.
真是麻烦
Gods.
天哪
You should've beheaded me while I was sleeping.
你应该趁我睡觉的时候砍掉我的头的
I am the son of Thors.
我是托尔兹之子
I could never do something…
我永远不会做
so cowardly!
这么懦夫的事情！
There you go!
好小子！
-He showed you, Askeladd! -Kill him, laddie!
他还真有一套啊 阿谢拉特！
You wanna be a grown-up warrior?
想像个成年战士一样吗？
Very well. Come at me.
那行 冲着我来
-That's right! -Just like that!
-对！ -就这样！
Damn it!
该死的！
You can't let a big sword like that swing you around.
你可不能让一把大剑拖着你晃荡
-No mercy! -He must be dead now, right?
-绝不留情 -他现在肯定死了 对吧？
We've confirmed the kill.
我们已经确认过他被杀了
Here's your gold.
这是你应得的黄金
My gratitude for bring it.
谢谢你们专程带过来
Say hello to Floki for me.
代我向佛洛基问好
No one said we had to get along with the villagers.
没人说过我们得和村民好好相处
That reminds me. We have a message for you.
这倒提醒了我 我们有话要问你
A message?
问我？
What was Thors's final moment like?
托尔兹最后的时刻是怎么样的？
Nothing special.
没什么特别的
His death was just like any other.
他的死和别人的没两样
You're still alive?
哦 你还活着啊？
You look awful.
你看起来很糟糕
Want some?
要吃点吗？
You'll get worse if you don't eat.
你不吃才对你不好
What's with him? I was only showing him goodwill.
他这是怎么了？ 我不过是想向他示示好
Damn it.
该死的
Damn it!
该死的！
He was glorious in his final moments.
他最后的时刻很光荣
Thors sacrificed himself for us.
托尔兹为了我们 牺牲了自己…
I'm sorry, Helga. Ylva.
赫尔加 攸尔法 我很抱歉
There are truly no words to express just how sorry I am.
我实在无法用语言来表达我的歉意
There's nothing you can do about death.
他的死 你无能为力
Sobbing will only make you hungry.
为此哭泣只会让你饥饿
Well then, I'd better get to work.
那好吧 我还是去干活吧
Helga.
赫尔加
I swear that I will find Thorfinn.
我发誓我一定会找到托尔芬
No matter how many years it takes.
无论那要用多少年
Well, I never thought he would live long anyway.
我反正从来没认为他能活很久
Father was so eccentric. He was bound to bring sorrow.
父亲是那么不同寻常 他肯定不会让我们好过
Your younger brother is missing too, right?
你弟弟也失踪了 对吧？
Are you okay, Ylva?
攸尔法 你没事吧？
Well, it'll be busy without men around.
男人们不在会很忙的
Ylva.
攸尔法…
-Here we go! -You're overdoing it, Ylva!
上路吧！
Mother, how are you feeling?
母亲 你感觉怎么样？
I'm feeling much better.
我好多了
-I'm sorry you have to do everything-- -Rest.
让你做所有事情 真是对不起…
It's okay. Just stay in bed.
没事的 你就待在床上吧
Oh, no. The sheep!
哦 不 羊群！
Yes, yes. I'm sorry I'm late.
我知道 我知道 抱歉我晚了
Once spring comes, I'll have to shear the sheep too.
春天一到 我还得给羊剃毛
Here I go!
我来了！
I harpooned it first!
是我先刺到的！
What a busy day.
今天真是好忙啊
We really need more help around here.
这里确实需要更多人
Maybe I'll take a husband.
也许我该找个丈夫
Thanks for all your hard work.
谢谢你的辛苦工作
Let's go to sleep.
我们睡觉去吧
You go ahead.
你先去吧
I want to finish this first.
我要先把这个弄完
But it's too dark to see your hands.
可是这么暗 你都看不到你的手了
You'll mar your weaving.
这样你会织错的
Ylva.
攸尔法
You've done enough.
你今天做得够多了
Let's rest.
休息吧
But it's just a little more.
还有一点点就好了
It's okay.
没事的
I'm not tired yet.
我还不累
I'll kill him.
我会杀了他
I swear I'll kill him.
我发誓我会杀了他
Hey.
嘿
You're working hard.
你练得很卖力啊
So?
怎么？
You learn how to use your sword?
习惯了你的剑了吗？
It's all because you used me as a shield!
都是因为你用我当你的掩护！
Father is…
父亲…
You coward!
你这个懦夫！
You father was certainly strong.
你父亲确实很强壮
But he was naive.
但他太天真了
That's all.
仅此而已
Do not mock my father!
不许嘲笑我父亲！
Well, you're too weak.
你呢 就是很弱
Hey.
嘿
I came across that kid in the forest.
我在树林里碰到了那个孩子
What? He's still alive?
什么？他还活着？
He's got the Troll of Jom's blood in him.
他身体里流淌着约姆的巨怪的血
He won't just drop dead.
他可不会就这么忽然死掉
Like father, like son.
有其父必有其子 对吧？
You can't let a big sword like that swing you around.
你可不能让这么一把大剑拖着你晃荡
Damn it!
该死的！
We stayed quite a while.
我们已经待了一段时间了
I'm feeling like myself again.
我现在已经完全恢复正常了
That village was most comfortable.
这个村子还挺舒服的
-Someone is approaching. -Huh?
有人在靠近
I am Thorfinn, son of Thors.
我是托尔芬 托尔兹之子
In the name of almighty Odin,
以全能的奥丁之名
I challenge you to a duel!
我向你发出决斗挑战！
Good grief, he's relentless.
老天啊 他怎么就是不肯罢休
But he's got guts, doesn't he?
他还挺有胆量的 不是吗？
Take him on, Askeladd!
阿谢拉特 你就跟他打吧！
It's settled.
就这么决定了
A leader shouldn't disappoint the expectations of his men.
首领的职责就是听取下属的意见
I, Askeladd, son of Olaf,
我 阿谢拉特 奥拉夫之子
accept your challenge in the name of Odin.
以奥丁之名接受你的挑战
I have no choice.
我别无选择
Good grief. Do you wish to see your father that badly?
老天呀 你就这么想去见你父亲吗？
-It's all over! -He can't win.
-就这么完蛋了！ -他赢不了
What? Finished already?
怎么？这就完了？
How boring.
真是无趣
Stand up!
站起来！
This is a duel, isn't it?
这可是决斗 不是吗？
Just let him go. He'll die at this rate.
让他走吧 这样下去他真的会死
What?
什么？
Weren't you the one prodding me to take him on?
不是你让我跟他打的吗？
I've had enough. I can't keep playing with you.
我受够了 我可不想继续陪你玩
Besides, I don't enjoy killing kids.
而且 我也不喜欢杀小孩
Why?
为什么？
What's with you?
你到底怎么回事？
I don't have time for this.
我也没空跟你聊天
Wait!
等等！
I haven't lost yet!
我还没输呢！
Fight me, you coward!
你个懦夫 跟我打！
You sure are a persistent brat.
你可真是个不肯放弃的小混蛋
I'm not finished yet!
我还没打完呢！
Not until I've killed you!
在杀掉你之前都不算完！
I swear I'll kill you!
我发誓我会杀了你！
Prove yourself on the battlefield.
去战场上赢一点战功
You're a Nordic warrior, aren't you?
你是个北欧战士 对吧？
Once you do that.
等你赢得了战功
I'll reward you with a duel.
我会奖励你一场决斗
Is that a promise?
你保证？
That's right. A warrior's promise.
没错
I'll prove myself soon.
我很快就会有所成就的
Soon…
很快
I'll…
我就…
kill you.
会杀了你
Subtitle translation by Astrid Oliver
字幕翻译：Zeo Niu